Finding Aid for G. Mennen Williams Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Governor's Papers
  - Chronological, 1949-1960
    - 1954
      - Boards and Commissions
        - Corrections Department
          - Inmates [G-T] (Box 131)
          - Inmates [U-Z] (Box 132)
          - Pardons and Commutation Files [A-Z] (Box 132)
          - Prisons and Reformatories
            - Reports (Box 132)
            - Ionia (Box 132)
            - Jackson (Box 132)
            - Livingston County Prison (Box 132)
            - Marquette (Box 132)
        - Cosmetology Board (Box 132)
        - Court of Claims (Box 132)
        - Crippled Children Commission (Box 133)
        - Dentistry, Board of (Box 133)
        - Economic Development Department
          - General (Box 133)
          - Michigan Week (Box 133)
        - Education, State Board of
          - General (Box 133)
          - School for Blind (Box 133)
          - School for Deaf (Box 133)
        - Employees Retirement Board, State (Box 133)
        - Michigan Employment Security Commission
          - Max Horton, Director (Box 133)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 133)
          - Employment Service (Box 133)
          - Citizen Mail [A-Z] (Box 133)
          - Appeal Board (Box 133)
        - Equalization Board (Box 134)
        - Escheats, State Board of (Box 134)
        - Fairs, Board of Managers of State (Box 134)
        - Fair, Upper Peninsula Board of Managers (Box 134)
        - Great Lakes Tidewater Commission (Box 134)
        - Health Commission
          - Albert Heustis, Commissioner (Box 134)
          - General (Box 134)
        - Highway, Department of
          - Charles Ziegler, Commissioner (Box 134)
          - Bond Meetings, December (Box 134)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 134)
          - Bridges and Ferries (Box 134)
        - Historical Commission (Box 135)
        - Hospital Survey and Construction (Box 135)
        - Huron-Clinton Metropolitan Authority (Box 135)
        - Insurance Commission (Box 135)
        - International Bridge Authority (Box 135)
        - Interstate Cooperation Commission (Box 135)
        - Judges Retirement Board (Box 135)
        - Judicial Council of Michigan (Box 135)
        - Labor Department (Box 135)
        - Labor Mediation Board
          - George E. Bowles, Chairman (Box 135)
          - Consumer's Power (Box 135)
          - Dearborn Coach Company (Box 135)
          - Michigan Gas and Electric Co., Three Rivers (Box 135)
        - Law Examiners, Board of (Box 135)
        - Library, State (Box 135)
        - Lieutenant Governor (Box 135)
        - Liquor Control Commission
          - George Burke, Jr., Commissioner (Box 135)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 135)
        - Mackinac Island Park Commission (Box 136)
        - Mackinac Straits Bridge Authority
          - General (Box 136)
          - Re Job (Box 136)
        - Medicine, Board of Registration (Box 136)
        - Mental Health Department
          - Charles Wagg, Director (Box 136)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 136)
          - National Governors' Conference on Mental Health, February 8-9, 3 folders (Box 136)
          - Central States Conference (Box 136)
          - Mid-west Governors' Conference, November 30 (Box 136)
          - Meeting, January 6 (Box 136)
          - Childrens Hospital (Box 136)
          - Recovery, Inc. (Box 136)
          - Hospitals (Box 137)
            - Caro (Box 137)
            - Coldwater (Box 137)
            - Ionia (Box 137)
            - Kalamazoo (Box 137)
            - Lapeer (Box 137)
            - Mt. Pleasant (Box 137)
            - Newberry (Box 137)
            - Northville (Box 137)
            - Pontiac (Box 137)
            - Traverse City (Box 137)
            - Ypsilanti (Box 137)
        - Mortuary Science Board (Box 137)
        - Municipal Employees Retirement Board (Box 137)
        - Municipal Finance commission (Box 137)
        - Nursing, Board of (Box 137)
        - Optometry, Board of Examiners (Box 137)
        - Osteopathic Registration and Examination, Board of (Box 137)
        - Pharmacy, Board of (Box 137)
        - Plumbing Board (Box 137)
        - Police, State
          - Joseph Childs, Commissioner (Box 137)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 137)
          - Holiday Traffic (Box 137)
        - Port of Detroit (Box 137)
        - Port of Monroe (Box 137)
        - Private Employment Bureaus (Box 137)
        - Public Instruction
          - C. L. Taylor, Superintendent (Box 137)
          - Higher Education Study (Box 137)
          - Meeting, February 25 (Box 138)
          - Teacher Shortage (Box 138)
          - White House Conference (Box 138)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 138)
        - Public School Employee Retirement Board (Box 138)
        - Public Service Commission
          - John McCarthy, Chairman (Box 138)
          - Panhandle Eastern Pipe Line Company (Box 138)
          - Ton-Mile Tax (Box 138)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 138)
        - Racing Commission (Box 138)
        - Revenue Department (Box 138)
        - Safety Commission
          - General (Box 139)
          - Meeting (Box 139)
        - Secretary of State
          - Owen J. Cleary (Box 139)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 139)
        - Social Welfare Commission
          - W. J. Maxey, Director (Box 139)
          - General (Box 139)
          - Reports (Box 139)
          - Aid to Blind (Box 139)
          - Aid to Dependent Children (Box 139)
          - Boys Vocational School (Box 139)
          - Children's Institute (Box 139)
          - Disabled Persons (Box 139)
          - Employment Institute for the Blind (Box 139)
          - Girls' Training School (Box 139)
          - Old Age Assistance
            - Claim on Property (Box 139)
            - General [A-C] (Box 139)
            - General [D-Z] (Box 140)
          - Social Welfare letters [A-Z] (Box 140)
        - Soil Conservation Commission (Box 140)
        - Soo Locks Centennial Commission (Box 140)
        - Supreme Court (Box 140)
        - Tax Commission (Box 140)
        - Tax Appeals, Board of (Box 140)
        - Tenure Commission (Box 140)
        - Tourist Council
          - General (Box 141)
          - Winter Sports (Box 141)
          - Area associations (Box 141)
        - Treasurer, State (Box 141)
        - Tuberculosis Sanitorium Commission (Box 141)
        - Turnpike Authority (Box 141)
        - Veterans Facility (Grand Rapids) (Box 141)
        - Vocational Education, Board of Control (Box 141)
        - Water Resources Commission
          - Milton Adams, Commissioner (Box 141)
          - General (Box 141)
          - Flood Control Commission (Box 141)
          - Great Lakes Level (Box 141)
          - St. Clair Pollution (Box 141)
        - Waterways Commission
          - General (Box 141)
          - Harbors of Refuge (Box 141)
        - Workmen's Compensation Commission (Box 141)
      - Legislative Files
        - Regular Session
          - Governor's Messages, 2 folders (Box 336)
            (and related)
          - Bills Signed (Box 336)
          - Bills Vetoed (Box 336)
          - Constituent Mail
            - General [A-Z] (Box 337)
            - Resolution 18 (Box 337)
            - Resolution J (Box 337)
            - Bulk Milk (H.B. 249) (Box 337)
            - Fortified Milk (H.B. 210) (Box 337)
            - Library Building (Box 337)
            - McCurie Bill (Box 337)
            - Municipally Operated Utilities (S.B. 1102) (Box 337)
            - Tax Exemption for Public Housing (H.B. 315) (Box 337)
            - Unemployment Compensation (Teahen Bill) (Box 337)
        - Emergency Appropriations Commission
          - June 2, 1954 (Box 337)
          - July 26, 1954 (Box 337)
          - December 17, 1954 (Box 337)
        - Special Session
          - August 18, 1954 (Box 337)
      - Military
        - Adjutant General (Box 381)
        - Military Board
          - General (Box 381)
          - Subcommittee (Box 381)
        - Civil Defense
          - Lester J. Maitland, State Director (Box 381)
          - General (Box 381)
          - Applications (Box 381)
          - Blood Typing (Box 381)
          - Council
            - General (Box 381)
            - Meetings (Box 381)
        - National Guard
          - General (Box 381)
          - Air Unit (Box 381)
          - Armories (Box 381)
          - Campaign (Box 381)
          - Navy (Box 381)
          - Windsor Church Parade (Box 381)
        - Veterans
          - General (Box 381)
          - Bonus (Box 381)
          - Employment (Box 381)
          - Hospitalization (Box 382)
          - General (Box 382)
          - Percy Jones Hospital (Box 382)
          - Organizations (Box 382)
          - Veterans Trust Fund
            - Report (Box 382)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 382)
        - Selective Service (Box 382)
      - Federal
        - Miscellaneous (Box 396)
        - U.S. Senate (Box 396)
        - Agriculture, Department of (Box 396)
        - Air Force (Box 396)
        - Army (Box 396)
        - Attorney General (Box 396)
        - Defense Mobilization (Box 396)
        - Federal Communications Commission (Box 396)
        - Federal Power Commission (Box 396)
        - Health, Education and Welfare, Department of (Box 396)
        - Housing (Box 396)
        - Interior, Department of
          - General (Box 396)
          - Indian Affairs (Box 396)
        - International Joint Commission (Box 396)
        - Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 396)
        - Labor, Department of (Box 396)
        - Navy, Department of (Box 396)
        - Postmaster General
          - General (Box 396)
          - Virgin Mary Stamp (Box 396)
        - Reorganization of Government (Box 396)
        - State, Department of (Box 396)
        - Legislation
          - Miscellaneous (Box 396)
          - Airport Development (Box 396)
          - Auto Excise Taxes (Box 396)
          - Bricker Amendment (Box 396)
          - Socialized Medicine
    - 1955
      - General Subjects
        - Achievements (Box 142)
        - Administrative Reorganization of Government (including earlier papers), 2 folders (Box 142)
        - Adoption (Box 142)
        - Adult Education (Box 142)
        - Advertising (Box 142)
        - Aging Commission (Box 142)
        - Airlines; Aviation (Box 142)
        - Alaska (Box 142)
        - American Korean Foundation (Box 142)
        - American Legion (Box 142)
        - Appointments (Box 142)
        - Articles for Publication (Box 142)
        - Atomic Energy Commission (see Conferences) (Box 142)
        - Atomic Energy Study Commission, 2 folders (Box 142)
        - Bar (State) (Box 142)
        - Boy Scouts (Box 142)
        - Capital Punishment (Box 142)
        - Celebrations (Box 142)
        - Certificate - Outgoing (Box 142)
        - Charter Amendments [A-C] (Box 142)
        - Charter Amendments [D-Z] (Box 143)
        - Citizenship Week (Box 143)
        - Communism (Box 143)
        - Community Chest (Box 144)
        - Complaints (Box 144)
        - Conferences
          - General (Box 144)
          - Atomic Energy Commission (Box 144)
          - National Rivers and Harbors (Box 144)
          - National Tax Conference (Box 144)
        - Constitution (Box 144)
        - Consulates (Box 144)
        - Council of State Governments (Box 144)
        - Counties [arranged alphabetically] (Box 144)
        - Countries [arranged alphabetically] (Box 144)
        - Detroit, City of (Box 144)
        - Disaster Relief (Box 144)
        - Displaced Persons (Box 145)
        - Divorce (Box 145)
        - Drains (Box 145)
        - Economic Advisory Council (Box 145)
        - Editorials (Box 145)
        - Educational Finance Study Commission (Box 145)
        - Elections
          - General (Box 145)
          - Fair Election Practices Commission (Box 145)
          - Voting Age (Box 145)
        - Emergency Industrial Production Commission
          - General (Box 145)
          - Washington Meeting (Box 145)
        - Employment [A-Z] (Box 145)
        - Executive Office (Box 145)
        - [Box number eliminated during the 1983-84 reprocessing of the Williams Collection] (Box 146)
        - Executive Order (Box 147)
        - Fair Employment Practices Commission (Box 147)
        - Flags (Box 147)
        - Friend of the Court (Box 147)
        - Fulbright Scholarship (Box 147)
        - Gambling (Box 147)
        - Governors' Conference (Box 147)
        - Governor's Mansion (Box 147)
        - Great Lakes Basin Compact (Box 147)
        - Hawaii (Box 147)
        - Hi-Y (Box 147)
        - Honorary Membership (Box 147)
        - Housing [A-Z] (Box 147)
        - Housing Study Commission (Box 147)
        - Immigration (Box 147)
        - Income Tax (Box 147)
        - Infantile Paralysis (Box 147)
        - Interagency Council for Recreation (Box 147)
        - Intergovernmental Relations (Box 147)
        - Interviews [A-Z] (Box 148)
        - Investigation (Box 148)
        - Invitations - Outgoing
          - General (Box 148)
          - Re: Centennials (Box 148)
        - Isle Royale Park Study Commission (Box 148)
        - Judgeship (Box 148)
        - Juvenile Delinquency (Box 148)
        - Labor (Box 148)
        - Legal Holidays (Box 148)
        - Legal Problems [A-L] (Box 148)
        - Legal Problems [M-Z] (Box 149)
        - Legislature, Members of
          - General (Box 149)
          - Open House, Jan. 13 (Box 149)
        - Lobbyists (Box 149)
        - Message of Governor (Box 149)
        - Messages of Greeting [A-Z] (Box 149)
        - Migrant Labor (Box 149)
        - Moody, Blair (Box 149)
        - Moral Re-armament (Box 149)
        - Music (Box 149)
        - Nationality Groups (Box 149)
        - Newspapers (Box 149)
        - Notary Public (Box 149)
        - Ordinances (Box 150)
        - Organizations
          - General (Box 150)
          - Israel Trip (Box 150)
        - Philippine Islands (Box 150)
        - Physically Handicapped (Box 150)
        - Political
          - General, 3 folders (Box 150)
          - Statement of G. Mennen Williams at Governors' Conference, 3 folders (Box 150)
        - Political Job (Box 150)
        - Postmaster (Box 150)
        - Price Control (Box 150)
        - Program Advisory Group (Box 150)
        - Public Utilities (Box 150)
        - Racial (Box 150)
        - Radio (Box 150)
        - Radio; TV (Box 150)
        - Recommendation (Box 151)
        - Red Cross (Box 151)
        - Red Stocking Club (Box 151)
        - Removal (Box 151)
        - Rent Control (Box 151)
        - Research Bulletins (Box 151)
        - Resolutions (Box 151)
        - Roads (Box 151)
        - Safety
          - General (Box 151)
          - Holiday Traffic (Box 151)
          - Meeting (Box 151)
          - S. D. Day (Box 151)
          - Speed Watch (Box 151)
          - Teen Age Safety (Box 151)
        - St. Lawrence Seaway (Box 152)
        - Savings Bonds (Box 152)
        - Sex Deviates
          - General (Box 152)
          - Barbara Gaca case (Box 152)
        - Sponsor
          - General (Box 152)
          - Hall of Fame (Box 152)
          - Truman Library (Box 152)
        - State Ferries Employment Advisory Committee, Michigan (Box 152)
        - Statements for Publication [A-Z] (Box 152)
        - States [arranged alphabetically] (Box 152)
        - Strikes (Box 152)
        - Taxation, 2 folders (Box 152)
        - Taxation, 2 folders (Box 153)
        - Transportation (Box 153)
        - Unemployment (Box 153)
        - Unions (Box 153)
        - United Nations (Box 153)
        - Vacancy (Box 153)
        - Water (Box 153)
        - Wayne University (Box 153)
        - Wayne University Study Committee (Box 153)
        - Wolverine Boys State (Box 153)
        - Wolverine Girls State (Box 153)
        - Young American Medals Committee (Box 153)
        - Youth Commission (Box 153)
        - Miscellaneous [A-C] (Box 153)
        - Miscellaneous [D-Z] (Box 154)
        - [Box number eliminated during the 1983-84 reprocessing of the Williams collection] (Box 155)
      - Boards and Commissions
        - Accident Fund (Box 156)
        - Accountancy, State Board of (Box 156)
        - Administrative Board
          - General (Box 156)
          - Meeting Files, Jan.-Oct. (Box 156)
          - Meeting Files, Nov.-Dec. (Box 157)
        - Administration, Department of
          - James W. Miller, Controller, 4 folders (Box 157)
          - General (Box 157)
          - Accounting Division (Box 157)
          - Building and Construction Division (Box 157)
          - Motor Transport Division (Box 157)
          - Property Manager Division (Box 157)
          - Purchasing Division
            - General (Box 157)
            - H. R. 3322 (Surplus Commodities) (Box 157)
            - Surplus Commodities (Box 157)
        - Aeronautics, Department of (Box 157)
        - Agriculture, Department of
          - George McIntyre, Director (Box 157)
          - Reports (Box 157)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 157)
          - Agricultural Council (Box 158)
          - Fairground (Box 158)
          - Meeting, Nov. 21 (Box 158)
          - Milk (Box 158)
        - Agriculture, State Board of (Box 158)
        - Alcoholism Board (Box 158)
        - Apple Commission (Box 158)
        - Architects, Board of Registration (Box 158)
        - Athletic, Board of Control (Box 158)
        - Attorney General
          - Thomas Kavanagh (Box 158)
          - General (Box 158)
          - Gasoline Prices (Box 158)
        - Auditor General
          - Victor Targonski (Box 158)
          - Reports (Box 158)
        - Banking Commission (Box 158)
        - Barbers, Board of Examiners (Box 158)
        - Basic Science, Board of Examiners (Box 158)
        - Building Commission (Box 158)
        - Canvassers Board (Box 158)
        - Cherry Commission (Box 158)
        - Chiropody, Board of Registration (Box 158)
        - Chiropractic Examiners, Board of (Box 158)
        - Civil Service Commission
          - A. G. Rasch File (Box 158)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 158)
        - Colleges, State
          - General (Box 159)
          - Private and Church Colleges (Box 159)
          - Central Michigan (Box 159)
          - Ferris State (Box 159)
          - Michigan College of Mining and Technology (Box 159)
          - Michigan State University
            - General (Box 159)
            - Centennial (Box 159)
            - Renaming (Box 159)
          - Michigan State Normal College (Box 159)
          - University of Michigan
            - General (Box 159)
            - University Hospital (Box 159)
        - Conservation Department
          - Gerald Eddy, Director (Box 159)
          - Reports (Box 159)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 159)
          - Interstate Oil Compact Commission (Box 159)
          - Lands Division (Box 159)
          - Parks and Recreation (Box 159)
          - TV (Mort Neff) (Box 159)
        - Corporation and Securities Commission (Box 159)
        - Corrections Department
          - Gus Harrison, Director (Box 160)
          - Reports (Box 160)
          - General (Box 160)
          - Inmates [A-L] (Box 160)
          - Inmates [M-Z] (Box 161)
          - Pardons and commutation Files [A-L] (Box 161)
          - Pardons and commutations files [M-Z] (Box 162)
          - Prisons and Reformatories
            - Ionia (Box 162)
            - Jackson (Box 162)
            - Marquette (Box 162)
        - Cosmetology Board (Box 162)
        - Court of Claims Commission (Box 162)
        - Crippled Children Commission (Box 162)
        - Dentistry, Board of (Box 162)
        - Economic Development Department
          - General (Box 162)
          - Michigan Week (Box 162)
          - Small Business Administration (Box 162)
        - Education, State Board of
          - General (Box 162)
          - School for Blind (Box 162)
          - School for Deaf (Box 162)
        - Employees Retirement Board, State
          - General (Box 162)
          - Re: Social Security (Box 162)
        - Michigan Employment Security Commission
          - Max Horton, Director (Box 163)
          - Reports (Box 163)
          - Advisory Council (Box 163)
          - General (Box 163)
          - Employment Service (Box 163)
          - Citizen Mail [A-Z] (Box 163)
          - Appeal Board (Box 163)
        - Equalization Board (Box 163)
        - Escheats, State Board of (Box 163)
        - Fairs, Board of Managers of State
          - General (Box 163)
          - Reports (Box 163)
        - Fair, Upper Peninsula Board of Managers (Box 163)
        - Fair Employment Practices Commission (Box 163)
        - Foresters Board of Registration (Box 163)
        - Great Lakes Commission (Box 163)
        - Health Commission
          - A. Heustis, Commissioner (Box 163)
          - General (Box 163)
          - Clinton River Pollution (Box 163)
          - Fluoridation (Box 163)
          - Salk Vaccine (Box 163)
        - Highway, Department of
          - Charles M. Ziegler, Commissioner (Box 164)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 164)
          - Bond Issue (Box 164)
          - Cement (Box 164)
          - Frankfort--Menominee Ferry (Box 164)
          - Turnpikes (Box 164)
        - Highway Reciprocity Board (Box 164)
        - Historical Commission
          - General (Box 164)
          - Hall of Fame (Box 164)
          - LaSalle Portrait (Box 164)
          - Stevens T. Mason Portrait (Box 164)
        - Hospital Survey and Construction (Box 164)
        - Huron-Clinton Metropolitan Authority (Box 164)
        - Insurance Commission
          - Joseph A. Navarre, Commissioner (Box 164)
          - General (Box 164)
          - Blue Cross (Box 164)
        - International Bridge Authority (Box 165)
        - Interstate Cooperation Commission (Box 165)
        - Judges Retirement Board (Box 165)
        - Judicial Council of Michigan (Box 165)
        - Labor Department (Box 165)
        - Labor Mediation Board
          - George E. Bowles, Commissioner (Box 165)
          - Calumet and Hecla Co. (Box 165)
          - Consumers Power (Box 165)
          - General Telephone Company (Box 165)
          - Pontiac City Lines (Box 165)
          - State Ferries (Box 165)
        - Law Examiners, Board of (Box 165)
        - Libraries, State Board of (Box 165)
        - Library, State (Box 165)
        - Lieutenant Governor (Box 165)
        - Liquor Control Commission
          - Frank Blackford, Chairman (Box 165)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 165)
        - Mackinac Island Park Commission (Box 165)
        - Mackinac Straits Bridge Authority (Box 165)
        - Medicine, Board of Registration
          - General (Box 165)
          - Michigan State Medical Society Liaison Committee (Box 165)
        - Mental Health Department
          - Charles Wagg, Director (Box 165)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 166)
          - Reports (Box 166)
          - Howell TB Sanitorium (Box 166)
          - Retarded Children (Box 166)
          - Thorazine (Box 166)
          - Hospitals
            - Caro (Box 166)
            - Coldwater (Box 166)
            - Ionia (Box 166)
            - Kalamazoo (Box 166)
            - Lapeer (Box 166)
            - Newberry (Box 166)
            - Northville (Box 166)
            - Pontiac (Box 166)
            - Traverse City (Box 166)
            - Ypsilanti (Box 166)
        - Mortuary Science Board (Box 166)
        - Municipal Employees Retirement Board (Box 166)
        - Municipal Finance Commission (Box 166)
        - Nurses and Trained Attendants, Board of Registration (Box 166)
        - Optometry, Board of Examiners
          - General (Box 166)
          - Julian D. Feiler dismissal (Box 166)
        - Osteopathic Registration and Examination, Board of (Box 166)
        - Pharmacy, Board of (Box 166)